http://www.rusu.co.uk/privacy-policy/

Freshers
What are you searching for?
1. Introduction
This privacy notice provides you with details of how we collect and process your personal data through your
use of our site rusu.co.uk, including any information you may provide through our site when
you purchase a product or service, sign up to our newsletter or take part in a prize draw or competition.
By providing us with your data, you warrant to us that you are over 13 years of age.
Reading University Students' Union (RUSU) is the data controller and we are responsible for
your personal data (referred to as "we", "us" or "our" in this privacy notice).
We have appointed a Data Protection Officer who is in charge of privacy related matters for us. If you have
any questions about this privacy notice, please contact the Data Protection Officer using the details set out
below.
Contact details
Our full details are:
Reading, RG6 6EH
If you are not happy with any aspect of how we collect and use your data, you have the right to complain to
the Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO), the UK supervisory authority for data protection issues (www.ico.org.uk). We should be grateful if you would
contact us first if you do have a complaint so that we can try to resolve it for you.
It is very important that the information we hold about you is accurate and up to date. Please let us know if
at any time your personal information changes by emailing us at marketing@rusu.co.uk
2. What data we collect about you
Personal data means any information capable of identifying an individual. It does not include anonymised
data.
We may process certain types of personal data about you as follows:
Identity Data
May include your first name, maiden name, last name, username, marital status, title, date of birth
and gender.
Contact Data
May include your billing address, delivery address, email address and telephone numbers.
Financial Data
May include your bank account and payment card details.
Transaction Data
May include details about payments between us and other details of purchases made by you.
Technical Data
May include your login data, internet protocol addresses, browser type and version, browser plug-in
types and versions, time zone setting and location, operating system and platform and other technology
on the devices you use to access this site.
Profile Data
May include your username and password, purchases or orders, your interests, preferences, feedback
and survey responses.
Usage Data
May include information about how you use our website, products and services.
Marketing and Communications Data
May include your preferences in receiving marketing communications from us and our third parties and
your communication preferences.
We may also process Aggregated Data from your personal data but this data does not reveal your identity and
as such in itself is not personal data. An example of this is where we review your Usage Data to work out the
percentage of website users using a specific feature of our site. If we link the Aggregated Data with your
personal data so that you can be identified from it, then it is treated as personal data.
Sensitive data
We do not collect any Sensitive Data about you. Sensitive data refers to data that includes details about
your race or ethnicity, religious or philosophical beliefs, sex life, sexual orientation, political opinions,
trade union membership, information about your health and genetic and biometric data. We do not collect any
information about criminal convictions and offences.
3. How we collect your personal data
We collect data about you through a variety of different methods including:
Direct interactions: You may provide data by filling in forms on our site (or otherwise)
or by communicating with us by post, phone, email or otherwise, including when you:
order our products or services;
create an account on our site;
subscribe to our service or publications;
request resources or marketing be sent to you;
enter a competition, prize draw, promotion or survey; or
give us feedback.
Automated technologies or interactions: As you use our site, we may automatically collect
Technical Data about your equipment, browsing actions and usage patterns. We collect this data by using
cookies, server logs and similar technologies. We may also receive Technical Data about you if you visit
other websites that use our cookies. Please see Section 11 regarding cookies for further details.
Third parties or publicly available sources: We may receive personal data about you from
various third parties and public sources as set out below:
Technical Data from the following parties: University of Reading
analytics providers such as Google based outside the EU;
search information providers Sprout Social and Issuu based outside the EU.
Contact, Financial and Transaction Data from providers of technical, payment and delivery services such
as MSL, Sagepay, 1&1 Internet Ltd based inside the EU.
4. How we use your personal data
We will only use your personal data when legally permitted. The most common uses of your personal data are:
Where we need to perform the contract between us.
Where it is necessary for our legitimate interests (or those of a third party) and your interests and
fundamental rights do not override those interests.
Where we need to comply with a legal or regulatory obligation.
Generally, we do not rely on consent as a legal ground for processing your personal data, other than in
relation to sending marketing communications to you via email or text message. You have the right to withdraw
consent to marketing at any time by emailing us at marketing@rusu.co.uk
Purposes for processing your personal data
Set out below is a description of the ways we intend to use your personal data and the legal grounds on which
we will process such data. We have also explained what our legitimate interests are where relevant.
We may process your personal data for more than one lawful ground, depending on the specific purpose for
which we are using your data. Please email us at marketing@rusu.co.uk if you need details about the specific legal
ground we are relying on to process your personal data where more than one ground has been set out in the
table below.
To process and deliver your order including:
Necessary for our legitimate interests to recover debts owed to us
To manage our relationship with you which will include:
Necessary for our legitimate interests to keep our records updated and to study how customers
use our products/services
To enable you to partake in a prize draw, competition or complete a survey
Necessary for our legitimate interests to study how customers use our products/services, to
develop them and grow our business
To administer and protect our business and our site (including troubleshooting, data analysis,
testing, system maintenance, support, reporting and hosting of data)
Identity
Contact
Technical
Necessary for our legitimate interests for running our business, provision of administration and
IT services, network security, to prevent fraud and in the context of a business reorganisation or
group restructuring exercise
Necessary to comply with a legal obligation
To deliver relevant content and advertisements to you and measure and understand the effectiveness
Necessary for our legitimate interests to study how customers use our products/services, to develop
them, to grow our business and to inform our marketing strategy
To use data analytics to improve our website, products/services, marketing, customer relationships
and experiences
Technical
Usage
Necessary for our legitimate interests to define types of customers for our products and services,
to keep our site updated and relevant, to develop our business and to inform our marketing strategy
To make suggestions and recommendations to you about goods or services that may be of interest to
Necessary for our legitimate interests to develop our products/services and grow our business
Marketing communications
You will receive marketing communications from us if you have:
requested information from us or purchased goods or services from us; or
if you provided us with your details and ticked the box at the point of entry of your details for us to
send you marketing communications; and
in each case, you have not opted out of receiving that marketing.
We will get your express opt-in consent before we share your personal data with any third party for marketing
purposes.
You can ask us or third parties to stop sending you marketing messages at any time by emailing us at marketing@rusu.co.uk at any time.
Where you opt out of receiving our marketing communications, this will not apply to personal data provided to
us as a result of a product/service purchase, warranty registration, product/service experience or other
transactions.
Change of purpose
We will only use your personal data for the purposes for which we collected it, unless we reasonably consider
that we need to use it for another reason and that reason is compatible with the original purpose. If you wish
to find out more about how the processing for the new purpose is compatible with the original purpose, please
email us at marketing@rusu.co.uk.
If we need to use your personal data for a purpose unrelated to the purpose for which we collected the data,
we will notify you and we will explain the legal ground of processing.
We may process your personal data without your knowledge or consent where this is required or permitted by
law.
5. Disclosures of your personal data
We may have to share your personal data with the parties set out below for the purposes set out in the table
in paragraph 4 above:
Other companies in our group who provide IT and system administration services and undertake leadership
reporting such as RUSU Trading Ltd and Little Learners Nursery
Service providers who provide IT and system administration services.
Professional advisers including lawyers, bankers, auditors and insurers who provide consultancy, banking,
legal, insurance and accounting services.
HM Revenue & Customs, regulators and other authorities based in the United Kingdom and other relevant
jurisdictions who require reporting of processing activities in certain circumstances.
Other third parties such as National Union of Students (NUS)
Third parties to whom we sell, transfer, or merge parts of our business or our assets.
We require all third parties to whom we transfer your data to respect the security of your personal data and
to treat it in accordance with the law. We only allow such third parties to process your personal data for
specified purposes and in accordance with our instructions.
6. International transfers
We do not transfer your personal data outside the European Economic Area (EEA).
7. Data security
We have put in place appropriate security measures to prevent your personal data from being accidentally
lost, used or accessed in an unauthorised way, altered or disclosed. In addition, we limit access to your
personal data to those employees, agents, contractors and other third parties who have a business need to know
such data. They will only process your personal data on our instructions and they are subject to a duty of
confidentiality.
We have put in place procedures to deal with any suspected personal data breach and will notify you and any
applicable regulator of a breach where we are legally required to do so.
8. Data retention
We will only retain your personal data for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes we collected it for,
including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, accounting, or reporting requirements.
To determine the appropriate retention period for personal data, we consider the amount, nature, and
sensitivity of the personal data, the potential risk of harm from unauthorised use or disclosure of your
personal data, the purposes for which we process your personal data and whether we can achieve those purposes
through other means, and the applicable legal requirements.
By law we have to keep basic information about our customers (including Contact, Identity, Financial and
Transaction Data) for six years after they cease being customers for tax purposes.
In some circumstances you can ask us to delete your data: see below for further information.
In some circumstances we may anonymise your personal data (so that it can no longer be associated with you)
for research or statistical purposes in which case we may use this information indefinitely without further
notice to you.
9 Your legal rights
Under certain circumstances, you have rights under data protection laws in relation to your personal data.
These include the right to:
Request access to your personal data.
Request correction of your personal data.
Request erasure of your personal data.
Object to processing of your personal data.
Request restriction of processing your personal data.
Request transfer of your personal data.
Right to withdraw consent.
You can see more about these rights at the ICO website.
If you wish to exercise any of the rights set out above, please email us at marketing@rusu.co.uk.
You will not have to pay a fee to access your personal data (or to exercise any of the other rights).
However, we may charge a reasonable fee if your request is clearly unfounded, repetitive or excessive.
Alternatively, we may refuse to comply with your request in these circumstances.
We may need to request specific information from you to help us confirm your identity and ensure your right
to access your personal data (or to exercise any of your other rights). This is a security measure to ensure
that personal data is not disclosed to any person who has no right to receive it. We may also contact you to
ask you for further information in relation to your request to speed up our response.
We try to respond to all legitimate requests within one month. Occasionally it may take us longer than a
month if your request is particularly complex or you have made a number of requests. In this case, we will
notify you and keep you updated.
10. Third-party links
This website may include links to third-party websites, plug-ins and applications. Clicking on those links or
enabling those connections may allow third parties to collect or share data about you. We do not control these
third-party websites and are not responsible for their privacy statements. When you leave our website, we
encourage you to read the privacy notice of every website you visit.
11. Cookies
When you use this website, we may collect information about your computer, such as your IP address and/or
browser, which we will use for administration purposes and statistical analysis. This information will not
usually identify you personally.
We may also obtain information about your online movements and use of the internet. We do this by placing a
'cookie', which is a small file, on your computer's hard disk. Cookies are used for several reasons:
to recognise you whenever you visit this website
to speed up access to this website (so you do not have to log on each time)
to store your personal preferences
to build a profile about you
to better target our marketing and advertising campaigns
The vast majority of web browsers accept cookies. However, you can change your browser settings so that
cookies are not accepted. If you do this, you may lose some of the functionality of this website.
